<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on Tucson Mesh Docs</title><link>/intro/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on Tucson Mesh Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Additional Resources</title><link>/intro/additional-resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/intro/additional-resources/</guid><description>Our network is constantly evolving. Things change as technology improves, people come and go, volunteer-run services are added or abandoned, and challenges are faced and overcome. While we strive to document as much as possible as thoroughly as possible, sometimes we miss things or our (small) documentation team simply cannot record things in our docs as quickly as they happen.
If you find that our docs are incomplete or inaccurate, don&amp;rsquo;t give up!</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>/intro/gettingstarted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/intro/gettingstarted/</guid><description>Please read our FAQ if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already.
Join the mesh
First you need to enter a new node request. This will add your address to our list of requests and put your location on our map. If you have multiple locations enter them separately. If you are within range of a (blue) supernode or hub node, and have line-of-sight, we may be able to connect you.
The easiest option is for our install team to come out and do the install.</description></item><item><title>Typical Installations</title><link>/intro/typical-installs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/intro/typical-installs/</guid><description>Please read our FAQ if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already.
The intention of this page is not to be technical but rather give to the non-technical person an understanding of a typical installation.
NYC Mesh is an &amp;ldquo;over the air&amp;rdquo; network. The aim is to connect rooftop to rooftop using different types of equipment based on geography and topology. And in doing so, to expand NYC Mesh network coverage to the next block and so on*.</description></item></channel></rss>