<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installs on Tucson Mesh Docs</title><link>/installs/</link><description>Recent content in Installs on Tucson Mesh Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/installs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Avoiding problems</title><link>/installs/problems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/problems/</guid><description>Alignment and wind We&amp;rsquo;ve had many antennas lose alignment in the wind. There&amp;rsquo;s a few simple things you can do to prevent this-
Use a socket and drill to tighten hose clamps fast. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to get the hose clamp tight with a screw driver. A socket and drill will get it really tight. You&amp;rsquo;ll need a socket set that has both american and metric sockets.
Put one layer of electrical tape under the hose clamp.</description></item><item><title>Equipment</title><link>/installs/equipment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/equipment/</guid><description>To connect to NYC Mesh, you will need to install wireless networking equipment on a rooftop or outside a window. This page lists a range of equipment and tools that are commonly used for typical installations. Before assembling any equipment, first carry out a site survey and make an install plan to narrow down the equipment you really need. For detailed information about specific routers, visit the hardware docs.
You can download a handy checklist of the equipment listed on this page here.</description></item><item><title>Etiquette Guide</title><link>/installs/etiquette/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/etiquette/</guid><description>for volunteer installers
As a volunteer installer, you are the public face of NYCMesh! Courtesy, respect, friendliness and professionalism will give new members a great first impression of our organization and will encourage them to become active contributors to our community.
Before the Install Check the weather forecast the day before the install. If you have to cancel due to weather conditions, inform the install team on slack, email the installee member and send them a link to reschedule their appointment.</description></item><item><title>Fiber to the apartment</title><link>/installs/fiber/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/fiber/</guid><description>The first step is to screw the ONT into the wall in a convenient place using drywall achors. The ONT we are currently using is the Ubiquiti &amp;ldquo;UFiber loco GPON CPE&amp;rdquo;
Only use white fiber inside apartments, never yellow or any other color. This is to better blend in with the wall. We have custom made 3mm white fiber with termination at one end.
Once the ONT is screwed into the wall, plug in the terminated end of the white fiber.</description></item><item><title>How to Crimp an Ethernet cable</title><link>/installs/crimping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/crimping/</guid><description>Here are some helpful videos on crimping. Like nearly everyone we use the T-568B standard
Video 1
Video 2</description></item><item><title>LinkNYC Kiosk</title><link>/installs/linknyc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/linknyc/</guid><description>We do not install LinkNYC Kiosk repeaters as they are not as reliable as a mesh connection. We still support DIY kiosk repeaters through our Slack group.
If you are too far away from an access point to get a good connection, you can use a directional router to connect to Link NYC. We recommend using a Mikrotik SXTsq G-5acD international version. The LinkNYC kiosks use DFS channels which, although legal and FCC approved, aren&amp;rsquo;t supported in some USA versions of hardware.</description></item><item><title>Member Install Form</title><link>/installs/memberform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/memberform/</guid><description>Installers, after completing a new member installation, fill in the form that you previously printed. Leave the completed &amp;ldquo;Member Install Form&amp;rdquo; with the new member.
the Form</description></item><item><title>NanoStationM5 Outdoor</title><link>/installs/nsm5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/nsm5/</guid><description>We have moved on from NanoStations NSM5&amp;rsquo;s. We&amp;rsquo;re mostly using Ubiquiti LiteBeams and MikroTik OmniTik or SXTsq devices on rooftops now. We still support existing NanoStation installs, so this article is for those people.
Hardware
The simplest install is to use an existing vertical pipe and the two plastic ties that are included with the router. Also a thick PVC pipe can be attached to a railing using clamps.
If you need to aim the router up or down you can use a nanobracket.</description></item><item><title>Network Number</title><link>/installs/nn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/nn/</guid><description>Enter the Install Number* below to get the NN that can be used to configure the rooftop antennas/routers. This can also be used with existing multiple apartment installs to figure out the network number (NN) for the roof/building you are connected to.
Install Number: *The Install Number is the number you received in an email right after you registered. If you can&amp;rsquo;t find the email with your Install Number please contact us.</description></item><item><title>Old CPE guide</title><link>/installs/cpe2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/cpe2/</guid><description>This explains in detail how to configure Ubiquiti sector clients (e.g. LiteBeamAC or NanoBeamAC) to work with Hub nodes (such as Node 1340). For further support use the #install channel on our Slack.
This is for reference only! New config instructions are here
New config instructions are here
Notable sites that can use this config: Supernode 1 (previously SN1 had a different config) Node 1340 (33 Saratoga Ave, serving Bed Stuy, Bushwick, Ridgewood, Crown Heights) Line of sight to: 40.</description></item><item><title>Query</title><link>/installs/query/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/query/</guid><description>This is for installers to query our install spreadsheet. This is password protected.
This uses simple matching for addresses. Type the number and street name, e.g. &amp;ldquo;123 Smith St&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t enter a complete address! For NN, install number and email it uses exact matches.
Search type: Address Email NN Install num Search for: Password:</description></item><item><title>Site Safety</title><link>/installs/safety/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/safety/</guid><description>Growing the mesh is important, but so is staying safe to install more nodes. These are general safety guidelines intended to address more common hazards on an install, but keep an eye out for risks even if they are not covered here.
What to Bring to Site In addition to standard installation equipment, bring the following gear to ensure safety on site:
Fully-charged cell phone First-aid kit Eye protection Gloves (optional, but may come in handy if moving anything dirty) Boots or sturdy closed-toed shoes (nothing fancy; they will get dirty) Sunblock and hat (in summer) Water Cold-weather apparel (in winter - rooftops tend to be windy) Allergy medication (consider indoor as well as outdoor allergens) Traveling to and from Site Be aware of your surroundings at all times.</description></item><item><title>Site surveys</title><link>/installs/surveys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/surveys/</guid><description>Site surveys for large buildings help us determine if wireless connection is possible and how we will run cable to apartments. Take photos at each step as you go through the building.
Mounting points on roof Identify the best mounting points on the roof.
Bandwidth test Take a battery and do a bandwidth test to the hub or hubs that they are planning to connect to
(This might not be possible if the mounting point is in the water tower)</description></item><item><title>Supernode 1 CPE</title><link>/installs/cpe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/cpe/</guid><description>The has been deprecated. Please go to hardware/config for much easier instructions.</description></item><item><title>Taking Panorama Photos</title><link>/installs/panoramas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/panoramas/</guid><description>A direct line of sight to a Supernode or hub node is required to connect to NYC Mesh. To help the install team determine whether a line of sight is possible, we ask new members to provide a panoramic photo of the view from their rooftop. We don&amp;rsquo;t do installs in windows, but DIY are welcome to try this.
Where to find the panorama photo function on your phone Most cell phone cameras have panoramic photo capability in camera mode.</description></item><item><title>TP-Link Indoor Router</title><link>/installs/tp-link/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/tp-link/</guid><description>An indoor router, connected by ethernet cable to the outdoor router, is required for an NYC Mesh member to connect their personal devices to the Internet. For volunteer-led installations, the install team will supply the new member with a TP-Link dual-band router.
Here the link to configure the router</description></item></channel></rss>