<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nodes on Tucson Mesh Docs</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/</link><description>Recent content in Nodes on Tucson Mesh Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Saratoga hub</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/node-1340/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/node-1340/</guid><description>Saratoga hub (1340) is a hub node located at 33 Saratoga Avenue in Brooklyn New York. The installation provides mesh and internet connectivity for building residents as well as large areas of the Bedford Stuyvesant and Bushwick neighborhoods.
Status https://stats.1340.nycmesh.net
Coverage Photos Hardware Description Model Manufacturer Quantity Router EdgePointR6 UBNT 1 Switch EdgePointR6 UBNT 2 Indoor AP UniFi Mesh UBNT 5 Powerline adapter AV2000 (2-port Gigabit) TP-LINK 4 Outdoor AP SXT Mikrotik 1 Outdoor AP Nanostation M5 UBNT 1 Wide area AP LiteAP 120 UBNT 4 Wide area station Litebeam AC UBNT 2 Application server Raspberry Pi RPi Foundation 1 Schematic Ethernet over power We needed to place wireless access points deep inside the building but did not have permission or budget to run new conduit.</description></item><item><title>Supernode 1</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/supernode1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/supernode1/</guid><description>Supernode 1 is located at 375 Pearl St, New York, NY. This site is located in lower manhattan on the old Verizon building.
Status https://stats.nycmesh.net
Coverage</description></item><item><title>Supernode 2</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/supernode2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/supernode2/</guid><description>⚠️ Supernode 2 is no longer active. The sector antennas were moved to Soft Surplus ⚠️
Supernode 2 (node 570) was located at 1196 Metropolitan Avenue in Brooklyn New York. On October 7th, 2018 it was taken down due to roof repair.
The information below is a point of reference for how supernode 2 was configured.
Status https://stats.570.nycmesh.net
Coverage Photos Hardware Description Model Manufacturer Quantity Router Hex PoE Mikrotik 1 Point-to-point radio AirFiber 24 UBNT 1 Point-to-point radio Nanobeam AC UBNT 1 Wide area AP LiteAP 120 UBNT 2 Indoor AP UniFi AP UBNT 1 Application server Raspberry Pi RPi Foundation 1 Inverter/Charger/ATS APS700HF Tripp Lite 2 Battery EXP12180 ExpertPower 1 Schematic Backhaul A pair of AirFiber 24s was donated to NYC Mesh and was deployed between 227 and 570 to provide Brooklyn with a near 1Gbps backhaul link to Supernode 1, the Manhattan area of the mesh and the internet.</description></item><item><title>Supernode 3</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/supernode3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/supernode3/</guid><description>The new Supernode 3 is located in Industry City, Brooklyn at the DataVerge (previously known as ColoGuard) datacenter.
Status to come
Coverage Antenna positions SN3 views North South</description></item><item><title>Supernode 4</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/supernode4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/nodes/supernode4/</guid><description>⚠️ Supernode 4 is no longer active. Supernode 4 was located at St. Francis School for the Deaf.
Location Coverage Photo</description></item></channel></rss>