<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware on Tucson Mesh Docs</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in Hardware on Tucson Mesh Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configs</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/config/</guid><description>List of devices we use and links to standard configs and firmware
This doc is in progress. Please add links below to the specific config instructions
Important: Note that we use a Network Number (or NN) from now on to configure devices. The Network Number is not the Install Number (or request number) you received when registering. You can find out your NN using your Install Number (request number) received by email when you registered.</description></item><item><title>60 GHz</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/60ghz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/60ghz/</guid><description>60 GHz is an unlicensed band that now has some cheap gigabit point to point (p2p) antennas that we are using.
60 GHz is extremely susceptible to &amp;ldquo;rain-fade&amp;rdquo;, which is why it is not used in licensed spectrum
Often these radios come with a 5GHz backup, which isn&amp;rsquo;t really useful for bandwidth but it will keep your link online during rain.
Ubiquiti There&amp;rsquo;s a very confusing range of Ubiquiti 60GHz. Basically there&amp;rsquo;s dishes and enclosed headlight looking ones</description></item><item><title>Chromebook</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/chromebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/chromebook/</guid><description>Chromebooks are good for installs as they are cheap and all you need is a browser and a terminal anyway.
To get a standard terminal you have to put the Chromebook in developer mode. This will also erase your login info and any local data.
Turn the Chromebook off
Turn it on while holding esc and ⟳ (escape and reload)
Wait for the next screen that says something like &amp;ldquo;Chrome OS is missing or&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Ethernet</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/ethernet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/ethernet/</guid><description>You must use black outdoor cable outside. Indoor cable will last about 6 months outside due to UV damage. We mostly use Ubiquiti ToughCable Pro CAT5.
There is one commonly used standard for crimping ethernet: T-568B. (oO-gB-bG-brBR)
source
A straight cable will work as long as both ends are the same configuration, but to stop confusion we only use the standard T-568B, which is the most common one in this country.</description></item><item><title>MikroTik NetPower 15FR</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/mikrotiknetpower15fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/mikrotiknetpower15fr/</guid><description>The NetPower 15FR is an outdoor 16 ethernet ports Switch with PoE output on one port. Since the device has a waterproof outdoor case, you can mount it on a tower, or in other outdoor locations.
It supports passive PoE input on 15 ports and passive PoE output on one. We successfuly used this device to Power one OmniTik POE 5 ac which in turn powered an SXTsq G-5acD and thus were able to connect 9 apartments to NYC Mesh.</description></item><item><title>MikroTik OmniTik 5 POE ac</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/mikrotikomnitik5ac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/mikrotikomnitik5ac/</guid><description>The Omnitik 5ac is an outdoor switch/router with a built-in 5Ghz 802.11ac access point, omnidirectional antenna, and 5 gigabit ethernet ports. Be sure to get the POE version. Here are the config instructions
The OmniTik serves a few purposes for us. We can plug in other devices such as a LiteBeam, or run cables down to apartments. It acts as an AP for the rooftop, and also runs our config of WDS and OSPF so it will mesh with other OmniTiks or SXTsqs within a few blocks</description></item><item><title>MikroTik PowerBox Pro</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/mikrotikpowerboxpro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/mikrotikpowerboxpro/</guid><description>The PowerBox Pro is an outdoor five gigabit ethernet port router with PoE output on four ports. Since the device has a waterproof outdoor case, you can mount it on a tower, or in other outdoor locations.
It also supports passive PoE input and passive or 802.3af/at PoE output. Ethernet ports 2-5 can power other PoE capable devices with the same voltage as applied to the unit. Less power adapters and cables to worry about!</description></item><item><title>MikroTik Specifics</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/mikrotikspecifics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/mikrotikspecifics/</guid><description>Mikrotik routers have a few interesting things to note in order to understand and use them well. This page documents those interesting pieces and might help clarify some things. This page will be referenced by other pages and should be Mikrotik general.
Device variants License Mikrotik software usually requires a license, though all Mikrotik devices come with an internal license, which varies with the model. This router comes with a Level 4 licnese which is sufficient for its use.</description></item><item><title>Mikrotik SXTsq G-5acD</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/sxtsqg5acd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/sxtsqg5acd/</guid><description>The SXTSQ 5acD (sxtsq) is a small client access antenna that is 802.11 standards compliant antenna (and also nstream mikrotik if available).
The device was released in early 2018 and is capable of gigabit-level speeds with 80Mhz wide 802.11ac wifi connections.
Please be sure to see MikroTik Specifics for extra info about Mikrotik devices, how to connect, etc.
Device specs are available at mikrotik.com.
Uses LinkNYC Kiosk connection Hub node connection (for standard 802.</description></item><item><title>New Hardware</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/newhardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/newhardware/</guid><description>Title goes here Description with a link</description></item><item><title>TP-Link Indoor Router</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/tplink/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/tplink/</guid><description>An indoor router, connected by ethernet cable to the outdoor router, is required for an NYC Mesh member to connect their personal devices to the Internet. For volunteer-led installations, the install team will supply the new member with a TP-Link Archer A6 or a TP-Link Archer A7.
Pre-Configuration Best Practices For volunteer installers
Before configuring, ask the user member to tell you:
Whether they would like to use the TP-Link router we supply or their own router A username and password for the router An SSID and password for the home wireless network TP-Link Archer A6 or A7 Router Configuration Instructions For volunteer installers and DIY installers</description></item><item><title>Try the new LTU sector</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/ltu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/ltu/</guid><description>Ubiquiti has a new &amp;ldquo;technology&amp;rdquo; which is the successor to AirMax , called LTU. (more about AirMax )
LTU and AirMax are not compatible. You need a different device/antenna to connect to the LTU sector.
We have one LTU sector mounted on the west side of 1340-Saratoga. Try it. Here the approximate coverage.
The sector is a LTU-Rocket radio and a AM-5ac21-60 antenna. It is positioned about 260o azimut, and it&amp;rsquo;s a 60o angle.</description></item><item><title>Ubiquiti EdgePoint R6</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/epr6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/epr6/</guid><description>The EP-R6 is an outdoor rooftop switch/router with 6 ports (5 GigE, 1 SFP). It supports PoE, but only Ubiquiti&amp;rsquo;s 24v Passive PoE style, not any of the fancier types.
It can be configured in switch mode (just a switch, with a management console) or routing mode (hub node setup, BGP, etc).
Device specs are available at store.ubnt.com.
Reset To factory reset an EP-R6, press and hold the reset button, by the ethernet plugs, for about 10 seconds until the eth4 LED begins to flash, then release the button.</description></item><item><title>Ubiquiti LiteAP Sector</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/liteap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/liteap/</guid><description>The confusingly named LiteAP (LAP-120) is a very good, cheap 120&amp;rsquo; sector antenna. 120&amp;rsquo; means you need three to get a full 360&amp;rsquo;. It used to be called a LiteBeam 5AC AP LBE-5AC-16-120, and is still named that on parts of their website.
We use it as a sector antenna for most hub and supernode installs. As with all Ubiquiti gear you need to flash it with the latest firmware first.</description></item><item><title>Ubiquiti LiteBeam AC</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/litebeamac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/litebeamac/</guid><description>The LiteBeamAC is a very good, cheap directional router. We use it for most rooftop installs. As with all Ubiquiti gear you need to flash it with the latest firmware first. Often they ship with old beta firmware, and the latest firmware usually gets you faster speeds. Our config instructions are here.
The AC in the name is not 802.11ac, it is Ubiquiti&amp;rsquo;s own protocol. These devices can only connect to other Ubiquiti &amp;ldquo;AC&amp;rdquo; devices.</description></item><item><title>Ubiquiti Nanostation M5</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/nsm5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/nsm5/</guid><description>The NanoStation M5 is a workhorse of mesh networks. There are two versions XM (pre 2016) and XW. It is 802.11n and 10/100 ethernet, so not the fastest on the block, but it has good support from OpenWRT. It also has two ethernet ports usually set up as WAN and LAN. Recent versions require downgrading AirOS before you flash.
For new installs we use the OmniTik router for meshing. The following page is mainly for our legacy installs.</description></item><item><title>Unifi Access Points</title><link>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/unifi-ap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mackncheesiest.github.io/tucsonmesh-docs/hardware/unifi-ap/</guid><description>We are using more UNIFI access points on installs these days. These devices are very frustrating to set up, so this document is designed to help.
As of 2021 the latest firmware 4.3.28 has very short uptime (&amp;lt;30 days), so we are using a stable older version 4.3.20 (copy this link)
Never use 4.3.28 or later, as the device will go down and require a site visit to reboot!
The devices are coming with very old firmware that isn&amp;rsquo;t even compatible with the controller so step one is to SSH into the AP and upgrade it to 4.</description></item></channel></rss>