<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on Tucson Mesh Docs</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on Tucson Mesh Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configs</title><link>/hardware/config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/config/</guid><description>List of devices we use and links to standard configs and firmware
This doc is in progress. Please add links below to the specific config instructions
Important: Note that we use a Network Number (or NN) from now on to configure devices. The Network Number is not the Install Number (or request number) you received when registering. You can find out your NN using your Install Number (request number) received by email when you registered.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting</title><link>/diy/troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/diy/troubleshooting/</guid><description>First step. Make sure all the devices are powered on. You may have two power supplies, one to power your home WiFi router and a second to power the poe (power over Ethernet) which in turn power the device(s) on the roof.
The poe is a device that power the devices on the roof through the Ethernet cable.
If you have only a WiFi router, then make sure it is powered and connected to the Ethernet cable coming from the roof.</description></item><item><title>Ubiquiti Firmware</title><link>/firmware/ubiquiti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/firmware/ubiquiti/</guid><description>Ubiquiti firmware has some buggy versions that need to be avoided. In general never use a &amp;ldquo;.0&amp;rdquo; release. It is beta quality and will probably have serious bugs that may be fixed by .1 or .2 version.
Ubiquiti have two very separate product lines with different firmware, AirMAX and UniFi
Don&amp;rsquo;t use the latest firmware from Ubiquiti! Use the stable versions below-
AirMAX
We currently use 8.7.1 on most CPE (like the LiteBeams)</description></item><item><title>MikroTik Firmware</title><link>/firmware/mikrotik/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/firmware/mikrotik/</guid><description>MikroTik routerOS 6 firmware is generally stable. We are using 6.47.8
Do not use version 7 or version 6.48
routerOS 6
Download 6.47.8 OmniTik (mipsbe) here and SXTsq (arm) here
Remember that OmniTiks use the &amp;ldquo;mipsbe&amp;rdquo; firmware and SXT&amp;rsquo;s use the &amp;ldquo;arm&amp;rdquo; firmware due to different processors.
We have had many crashes with 6.48 so don&amp;rsquo;t use it.
We are testing some omnitiks with 6.49.2 but this is also not recommended</description></item><item><title>10-69-net Network</title><link>/networking/10-69-net-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/10-69-net-network/</guid><description>The 10-69 network is used to connect nodes on NYC Mesh. Every mesh router at every node on the mesh gets an IP address from 10.69.0.0/16. Each router&amp;rsquo;s IP address can be computed from the router&amp;rsquo;s node number. The 10-69 network supports up to two routers per node.
The 10-69 network allows for routers at nodes to auto-discover each other using OSPF with minimal configuration. This makes it possible for anyone to join the mesh with almost no intervention from other mesh members.</description></item><item><title>60 GHz</title><link>/hardware/60ghz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/60ghz/</guid><description>60 GHz is an unlicensed band that now has some cheap gigabit point to point (p2p) antennas that we are using.
60 GHz is extremely susceptible to &amp;ldquo;rain-fade&amp;rdquo;, which is why it is not used in licensed spectrum
Often these radios come with a 5GHz backup, which isn&amp;rsquo;t really useful for bandwidth but it will keep your link online during rain.
Ubiquiti There&amp;rsquo;s a very confusing range of Ubiquiti 60GHz. Basically there&amp;rsquo;s dishes and enclosed headlight looking ones</description></item><item><title>Additional Resources</title><link>/intro/additional-resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/intro/additional-resources/</guid><description>Our network is constantly evolving. Things change as technology improves, people come and go, volunteer-run services are added or abandoned, and challenges are faced and overcome. While we strive to document as much as possible as thoroughly as possible, sometimes we miss things or our (small) documentation team simply cannot record things in our docs as quickly as they happen.
If you find that our docs are incomplete or inaccurate, don&amp;rsquo;t give up!</description></item><item><title>Avoiding problems</title><link>/installs/problems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/problems/</guid><description>Alignment and wind We&amp;rsquo;ve had many antennas lose alignment in the wind. There&amp;rsquo;s a few simple things you can do to prevent this-
Use a socket and drill to tighten hose clamps fast. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to get the hose clamp tight with a screw driver. A socket and drill will get it really tight. You&amp;rsquo;ll need a socket set that has both american and metric sockets.
Put one layer of electrical tape under the hose clamp.</description></item><item><title>BGP</title><link>/networking/bgp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/bgp/</guid><description>The Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) is an inter-Autonomous System routing protocol.
NYC Mesh no longer uses BGP within the mesh between neighbors / members. Use of BGP within the mesh was too static for the changing network, lacked some &amp;ldquo;automatic&amp;rdquo; properties, and made it difficult to train new people.
Use outside NYC Mesh BGP is a popular dynamic routing protocol as it is relatively simple to configure, scales well and enjoys support across multiple hardware and software vendors.</description></item><item><title>Chromebook</title><link>/hardware/chromebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/chromebook/</guid><description>Chromebooks are good for installs as they are cheap and all you need is a browser and a terminal anyway.
To get a standard terminal you have to put the Chromebook in developer mode. This will also erase your login info and any local data.
Turn the Chromebook off
Turn it on while holding esc and ⟳ (escape and reload)
Wait for the next screen that says something like &amp;ldquo;Chrome OS is missing or&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Classes</title><link>/networking/classes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/classes/</guid><description>We have presented a few classes on network concepts and training. Here is a list of slides and videos we have made for reference.
Networking 101 version 1, by Zach Giles, Early 2017 Slides
Networking 101 version 2, by Zach Giles, December 2018 Slides, Video</description></item><item><title>Culture</title><link>/organization/culture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/organization/culture/</guid><description>In a decentralized organization like the Mesh, it is difficult for new people to figure out who does what.
Basically we work on a system of trust. As we get to know new people we trust that they will do the right thing, and we gradually share access to locations and machines, and let them lead installs. During Covid it is obviously difficult to get to know people since we don&amp;rsquo;t get to socialize with everyone at our meetups, so zooms are the new way.</description></item><item><title>Custom Firmware (old)</title><link>/firmware/custom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/firmware/custom/</guid><description>Old firmware Repositories Old firmware build instructions are in our nycmeshfeed repo&amp;rsquo;s README file.
lime-sdk nycmeshfeed network-profiles</description></item><item><title>DNS</title><link>/networking/dns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/dns/</guid><description>DNS Infrastructure NYCMesh maintains an internal DNS with the &amp;ldquo;fake&amp;rdquo; top-level domain (TLD) of .mesh ( dot mesh ).
Through this, services can be hosted, internal sites, etc.
Use 10.10.10.10 for your DNS server.
DNS configuration The DNS is hosted using standard DNS zones which are made available through the Knot Resolver and Knot DNS Server.
The zone and scripts are made available via git. Once the master branch is updated, the DNS servers will periodically update and refresh their configuration.</description></item><item><title>Equipment</title><link>/installs/equipment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/equipment/</guid><description>To connect to NYC Mesh, you will need to install wireless networking equipment on a rooftop or outside a window. This page lists a range of equipment and tools that are commonly used for typical installations. Before assembling any equipment, first carry out a site survey and make an install plan to narrow down the equipment you really need. For detailed information about specific routers, visit the hardware docs.
You can download a handy checklist of the equipment listed on this page here.</description></item><item><title>Ethernet</title><link>/hardware/ethernet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/ethernet/</guid><description>You must use black outdoor cable outside. Indoor cable will last about 6 months outside due to UV damage. We mostly use Ubiquiti ToughCable Pro CAT5.
There is one commonly used standard for crimping ethernet: T-568B. (oO-gB-bG-brBR)
source
A straight cable will work as long as both ends are the same configuration, but to stop confusion we only use the standard T-568B, which is the most common one in this country.</description></item><item><title>Etiquette Guide</title><link>/installs/etiquette/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/etiquette/</guid><description>for volunteer installers
As a volunteer installer, you are the public face of NYCMesh! Courtesy, respect, friendliness and professionalism will give new members a great first impression of our organization and will encourage them to become active contributors to our community.
Before the Install Check the weather forecast the day before the install. If you have to cancel due to weather conditions, inform the install team on slack, email the installee member and send them a link to reschedule their appointment.</description></item><item><title>Fiber to the apartment</title><link>/installs/fiber/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/fiber/</guid><description>The first step is to screw the ONT into the wall in a convenient place using drywall achors. The ONT we are currently using is the Ubiquiti &amp;ldquo;UFiber loco GPON CPE&amp;rdquo;
Only use white fiber inside apartments, never yellow or any other color. This is to better blend in with the wall. We have custom made 3mm white fiber with termination at one end.
Once the ONT is screwed into the wall, plug in the terminated end of the white fiber.</description></item><item><title>Flashing Nanostation M5 with NYC Mesh Firmware</title><link>/software/nsm5-flash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/software/nsm5-flash/</guid><description>We have been moving towards MikroTik OmniTik as our mesh device. Before using a NanoStation, you should check with us that you are in range of another NanoStation. Some use the NanoStation when they are out of range of the mesh network using the built-in tinc vpn connection.
Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to read our FAQ on the main site.
Also, please fill out the Join form.
When finished, read how to install a NanoStation outdoors</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>/intro/gettingstarted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/intro/gettingstarted/</guid><description>Please read our FAQ if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already.
Join the mesh
First you need to enter a new node request. This will add your address to our list of requests and put your location on our map. If you have multiple locations enter them separately. If you are within range of a (blue) supernode or hub node, and have line-of-sight, we may be able to connect you.
The easiest option is for our install team to come out and do the install.</description></item><item><title>How to Crimp an Ethernet cable</title><link>/installs/crimping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/crimping/</guid><description>Here are some helpful videos on crimping. Like nearly everyone we use the T-568B standard
Video 1
Video 2</description></item><item><title>Hubs</title><link>/networking/hubs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/hubs/</guid><description>Hubs provide connectivity for many nodes in a neighborhood. They come in three different sizes: small, medium, and large. These categories are not strict, and you will find many variants in the field. You can modify your hub to suit your needs and the needs of other mesh members in your area.
Small The smallest possible hub is a standard node, an OmniTik 5 POE ac, with an added LiteBeam AC connected to a sector antenna at another hub or supernode to give it a reliable upstream connection.</description></item><item><title>IP Mapping Idea</title><link>/networking/ipmappingidea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/ipmappingidea/</guid><description>Hi #architecture, I&amp;#39;d like to propose an algorithm for making a Node Number to IP mapping programmatically. This is not a *new* idea. Several of us have thought about it and taken a stab at it, and I&amp;#39;d like to officially see if we can all agree on one. Also, the below ideas represent generally a few models of what can be done. There are infinite variations, but the generally follow the below pattern.</description></item><item><title>LinkNYC Kiosk</title><link>/installs/linknyc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/linknyc/</guid><description>We do not install LinkNYC Kiosk repeaters as they are not as reliable as a mesh connection. We still support DIY kiosk repeaters through our Slack group.
If you are too far away from an access point to get a good connection, you can use a directional router to connect to Link NYC. We recommend using a Mikrotik SXTsq G-5acD international version. The LinkNYC kiosks use DFS channels which, although legal and FCC approved, aren&amp;rsquo;t supported in some USA versions of hardware.</description></item><item><title>Master Plan</title><link>/organization/plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/organization/plan/</guid><description>Our basic plan is to create hubs and supernodes across the city so it is easy for any building to connect to our network. We think this will take about 50 tall buildings spread across all neighborhoods. We currently only have 3 supernodes and about 5 major hub nodes, so we are still a few years away from our goal.
This is a presentation from early 2018 on the technical side of the master plan.</description></item><item><title>Member Install Form</title><link>/installs/memberform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/memberform/</guid><description>Installers, after completing a new member installation, fill in the form that you previously printed. Leave the completed &amp;ldquo;Member Install Form&amp;rdquo; with the new member.
the Form</description></item><item><title>Mesh Design</title><link>/networking/mesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/mesh/</guid><description>NYC Mesh is designed and run as a mesh network. As a mesh, various nodes connect to each other in a non-hierarchical way, with traffic flowing in either direction, and rerouting traffic as nodes fail.
As with all mesh networks, we must balance between becoming too much of a &amp;ldquo;star&amp;rdquo; topology vs a &amp;ldquo;mesh&amp;rdquo; topology.
Neither is fully practical &amp;ndash; Not literally every node next to each other can all connect to each other, nor can we sustain unlimited nodes connecting to one rooftop.</description></item><item><title>MikroTik Netinstall Recovery</title><link>/firmware/mikrotik_netinstall_recovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/firmware/mikrotik_netinstall_recovery/</guid><description>How to resurrect a bootlooping OmniTIK with netinstall Symptoms OmniTIK boots up but continually reboots. The LEDs repeat the pattern: device boots up, power eventually turns blue, then 1-5 turn orange and reboots. Rinse and repeat.
Solution Use netinstall to flash a fresh firmware on the router. This guide assumes Linux, though both Linux and Windows are supported. This should work for any RouterBOARD based device.
Install netinstall on your laptop from mikrotik, and make sure it is in your command line path Download the firmware you want to reset to (e.</description></item><item><title>MikroTik NetPower 15FR</title><link>/hardware/mikrotiknetpower15fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/mikrotiknetpower15fr/</guid><description>The NetPower 15FR is an outdoor 16 ethernet ports Switch with PoE output on one port. Since the device has a waterproof outdoor case, you can mount it on a tower, or in other outdoor locations.
It supports passive PoE input on 15 ports and passive PoE output on one. We successfuly used this device to Power one OmniTik POE 5 ac which in turn powered an SXTsq G-5acD and thus were able to connect 9 apartments to NYC Mesh.</description></item><item><title>MikroTik OmniTik 5 POE ac</title><link>/hardware/mikrotikomnitik5ac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/mikrotikomnitik5ac/</guid><description>The Omnitik 5ac is an outdoor switch/router with a built-in 5Ghz 802.11ac access point, omnidirectional antenna, and 5 gigabit ethernet ports. Be sure to get the POE version. Here are the config instructions
The OmniTik serves a few purposes for us. We can plug in other devices such as a LiteBeam, or run cables down to apartments. It acts as an AP for the rooftop, and also runs our config of WDS and OSPF so it will mesh with other OmniTiks or SXTsqs within a few blocks</description></item><item><title>MikroTik PowerBox Pro</title><link>/hardware/mikrotikpowerboxpro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/mikrotikpowerboxpro/</guid><description>The PowerBox Pro is an outdoor five gigabit ethernet port router with PoE output on four ports. Since the device has a waterproof outdoor case, you can mount it on a tower, or in other outdoor locations.
It also supports passive PoE input and passive or 802.3af/at PoE output. Ethernet ports 2-5 can power other PoE capable devices with the same voltage as applied to the unit. Less power adapters and cables to worry about!</description></item><item><title>MikroTik Specifics</title><link>/hardware/mikrotikspecifics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/mikrotikspecifics/</guid><description>Mikrotik routers have a few interesting things to note in order to understand and use them well. This page documents those interesting pieces and might help clarify some things. This page will be referenced by other pages and should be Mikrotik general.
Device variants License Mikrotik software usually requires a license, though all Mikrotik devices come with an internal license, which varies with the model. This router comes with a Level 4 licnese which is sufficient for its use.</description></item><item><title>Mikrotik SXTsq G-5acD</title><link>/hardware/sxtsqg5acd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/sxtsqg5acd/</guid><description>The SXTSQ 5acD (sxtsq) is a small client access antenna that is 802.11 standards compliant antenna (and also nstream mikrotik if available).
The device was released in early 2018 and is capable of gigabit-level speeds with 80Mhz wide 802.11ac wifi connections.
Please be sure to see MikroTik Specifics for extra info about Mikrotik devices, how to connect, etc.
Device specs are available at mikrotik.com.
Uses LinkNYC Kiosk connection Hub node connection (for standard 802.</description></item><item><title>NanoStationM5 Outdoor</title><link>/installs/nsm5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/nsm5/</guid><description>We have moved on from NanoStations NSM5&amp;rsquo;s. We&amp;rsquo;re mostly using Ubiquiti LiteBeams and MikroTik OmniTik or SXTsq devices on rooftops now. We still support existing NanoStation installs, so this article is for those people.
Hardware
The simplest install is to use an existing vertical pipe and the two plastic ties that are included with the router. Also a thick PVC pipe can be attached to a railing using clamps.
If you need to aim the router up or down you can use a nanobracket.</description></item><item><title>Network Number</title><link>/installs/nn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/nn/</guid><description>Enter the Install Number* below to get the NN that can be used to configure the rooftop antennas/routers. This can also be used with existing multiple apartment installs to figure out the network number (NN) for the roof/building you are connected to.
Install Number: *The Install Number is the number you received in an email right after you registered. If you can&amp;rsquo;t find the email with your Install Number please contact us.</description></item><item><title>New Hardware</title><link>/hardware/newhardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/newhardware/</guid><description>Title goes here Description with a link</description></item><item><title>NTP Network Time Protocol</title><link>/networking/ntp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/ntp/</guid><description>NTP Infrastructure NYCMesh does not have yet a Mesh NTP server but 2 mesh members are providing NTP function on their server.
Use 10.10.10.123 as your NTP server address.
What is NTP The Netwok Time Protocol is a &amp;ldquo;network&amp;rdquo; protocol for devices to sych their clocks. See Wiki
IPs 10.10.10.123 - NTP for the mesh ( Use this one )
NTP stats and status Here are some stats on the NTP servers: NTP server hosted at SN3 NTP server hosted in Manhattan (it has a Stratum 1 receiver).</description></item><item><title>Old CPE guide</title><link>/installs/cpe2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/cpe2/</guid><description>This explains in detail how to configure Ubiquiti sector clients (e.g. LiteBeamAC or NanoBeamAC) to work with Hub nodes (such as Node 1340). For further support use the #install channel on our Slack.
This is for reference only! New config instructions are here
New config instructions are here
Notable sites that can use this config: Supernode 1 (previously SN1 had a different config) Node 1340 (33 Saratoga Ave, serving Bed Stuy, Bushwick, Ridgewood, Crown Heights) Line of sight to: 40.</description></item><item><title>OSPF</title><link>/networking/ospf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/ospf/</guid><description>Open Shortest Path First (OSPF) is a dynamic routing protocol. It uses a link state routing algorithm, thus, it performs functions such as detecting topology changes and link failures. It generally converges quickly and in a loop-free manner. OSPF is often used in corporate networks within a datacenter or building.
While OSPF is not generally used as a mesh protocol across a city, it has properties similar to other mesh protocols such as use of link state routing algorithms and auto-convergence.</description></item><item><title>Outreach Materials</title><link>/organization/outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/organization/outreach/</guid><description>NYC Mesh Member Guide (digital)
NYC Mesh Member Guide (print)
Flyers/Brochures
Two page trifold neighborhood brochure (English/Spanish)
Two page trifold general brochure
One page general flyer
Building Postcard (English/Spanish)
Building Postcard [Chinese]
One page narrow brochure: Join NYC Mesh
Tri-fold brochure
Church handout -(source file)
Thank you card
Letter Templates
Fiber install for building
Sample introductory letter for businesses/community organizations
Proposal to building management/landlord
Our logo
NYC Mesh logo svg</description></item><item><title>Protecting the Mesh</title><link>/organization/protecting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/organization/protecting/</guid><description>A common misconception about the mesh is that we are an &amp;ldquo;Internet Service Provider&amp;rdquo;, strictly speaking. While we provide an alternative connection to the Internet and thus serve as an alternative to the big NYC ISPs, we are first and foremost a community that supports a community network.
That being said, reliability is something we are trying to push into the 99.9 percentile as the vast majority of members rely on this network for their daily lives.</description></item><item><title>Public ASN Peering</title><link>/networking/peering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/peering/</guid><description>NYC Mesh operates AS395853 Our peering Policy is Yes Please contact us to peer with our network.
Note this this is our Public ASN, not the Mesh Network itself.
This community-run public network supplies NYC Mesh with net-neutral internet connectivity to support the community. If you would like to join the Mesh Network, please visit our Join Page make use of this network.
Peering Policy
NYC Mesh has an open peering policy.</description></item><item><title>Query</title><link>/installs/query/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/query/</guid><description>This is for installers to query our install spreadsheet. This is password protected.
This uses simple matching for addresses. Type the number and street name, e.g. &amp;ldquo;123 Smith St&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t enter a complete address! For NN, install number and email it uses exact matches.
Search type: Address Email NN Install num Search for: Password:</description></item><item><title>Saratoga hub</title><link>/nodes/node-1340/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/nodes/node-1340/</guid><description>Saratoga hub (1340) is a hub node located at 33 Saratoga Avenue in Brooklyn New York. The installation provides mesh and internet connectivity for building residents as well as large areas of the Bedford Stuyvesant and Bushwick neighborhoods.
Status https://stats.1340.nycmesh.net
Coverage Photos Hardware Description Model Manufacturer Quantity Router EdgePointR6 UBNT 1 Switch EdgePointR6 UBNT 2 Indoor AP UniFi Mesh UBNT 5 Powerline adapter AV2000 (2-port Gigabit) TP-LINK 4 Outdoor AP SXT Mikrotik 1 Outdoor AP Nanostation M5 UBNT 1 Wide area AP LiteAP 120 UBNT 4 Wide area station Litebeam AC UBNT 2 Application server Raspberry Pi RPi Foundation 1 Schematic Ethernet over power We needed to place wireless access points deep inside the building but did not have permission or budget to run new conduit.</description></item><item><title>Site Safety</title><link>/installs/safety/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/safety/</guid><description>Growing the mesh is important, but so is staying safe to install more nodes. These are general safety guidelines intended to address more common hazards on an install, but keep an eye out for risks even if they are not covered here.
What to Bring to Site In addition to standard installation equipment, bring the following gear to ensure safety on site:
Fully-charged cell phone First-aid kit Eye protection Gloves (optional, but may come in handy if moving anything dirty) Boots or sturdy closed-toed shoes (nothing fancy; they will get dirty) Sunblock and hat (in summer) Water Cold-weather apparel (in winter - rooftops tend to be windy) Allergy medication (consider indoor as well as outdoor allergens) Traveling to and from Site Be aware of your surroundings at all times.</description></item><item><title>Site surveys</title><link>/installs/surveys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/surveys/</guid><description>Site surveys for large buildings help us determine if wireless connection is possible and how we will run cable to apartments. Take photos at each step as you go through the building.
Mounting points on roof Identify the best mounting points on the roof.
Bandwidth test Take a battery and do a bandwidth test to the hub or hubs that they are planning to connect to
(This might not be possible if the mounting point is in the water tower)</description></item><item><title>Supernode 1</title><link>/nodes/supernode1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/nodes/supernode1/</guid><description>Supernode 1 is located at 375 Pearl St, New York, NY. This site is located in lower manhattan on the old Verizon building.
Status https://stats.nycmesh.net
Coverage</description></item><item><title>Supernode 1 CPE</title><link>/installs/cpe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/cpe/</guid><description>The has been deprecated. Please go to hardware/config for much easier instructions.</description></item><item><title>Supernode 2</title><link>/nodes/supernode2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/nodes/supernode2/</guid><description>⚠️ Supernode 2 is no longer active. The sector antennas were moved to Soft Surplus ⚠️
Supernode 2 (node 570) was located at 1196 Metropolitan Avenue in Brooklyn New York. On October 7th, 2018 it was taken down due to roof repair.
The information below is a point of reference for how supernode 2 was configured.
Status https://stats.570.nycmesh.net
Coverage Photos Hardware Description Model Manufacturer Quantity Router Hex PoE Mikrotik 1 Point-to-point radio AirFiber 24 UBNT 1 Point-to-point radio Nanobeam AC UBNT 1 Wide area AP LiteAP 120 UBNT 2 Indoor AP UniFi AP UBNT 1 Application server Raspberry Pi RPi Foundation 1 Inverter/Charger/ATS APS700HF Tripp Lite 2 Battery EXP12180 ExpertPower 1 Schematic Backhaul A pair of AirFiber 24s was donated to NYC Mesh and was deployed between 227 and 570 to provide Brooklyn with a near 1Gbps backhaul link to Supernode 1, the Manhattan area of the mesh and the internet.</description></item><item><title>Supernode 3</title><link>/nodes/supernode3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/nodes/supernode3/</guid><description>The new Supernode 3 is located in Industry City, Brooklyn at the DataVerge (previously known as ColoGuard) datacenter.
Status to come
Coverage Antenna positions SN3 views North South</description></item><item><title>Supernode 4</title><link>/nodes/supernode4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/nodes/supernode4/</guid><description>⚠️ Supernode 4 is no longer active. Supernode 4 was located at St. Francis School for the Deaf.
Location Coverage Photo</description></item><item><title>Supernode Architecture</title><link>/networking/supernode-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/supernode-architecture/</guid><description>Goals of this documents Supernode routing / goals Supernode sample architectures Plan to get us to this architecture Supernode routing / goals &amp;ldquo;If you can get to a supernode, you can get to the rest of the mesh ( and the internet ).&amp;rdquo;
A supernode should be the regional authority on how to get to its region, other regions, and the internet. Translate region-local rooftop-to-rooftop protocol routes to standard routes for other regions and vice versa.</description></item><item><title>Taking Panorama Photos</title><link>/installs/panoramas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/panoramas/</guid><description>A direct line of sight to a Supernode or hub node is required to connect to NYC Mesh. To help the install team determine whether a line of sight is possible, we ask new members to provide a panoramic photo of the view from their rooftop. We don&amp;rsquo;t do installs in windows, but DIY are welcome to try this.
Where to find the panorama photo function on your phone Most cell phone cameras have panoramic photo capability in camera mode.</description></item><item><title>TP-Link Indoor Router</title><link>/hardware/tplink/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/tplink/</guid><description>An indoor router, connected by ethernet cable to the outdoor router, is required for an NYC Mesh member to connect their personal devices to the Internet. For volunteer-led installations, the install team will supply the new member with a TP-Link Archer A6 or a TP-Link Archer A7.
Pre-Configuration Best Practices For volunteer installers
Before configuring, ask the user member to tell you:
Whether they would like to use the TP-Link router we supply or their own router A username and password for the router An SSID and password for the home wireless network TP-Link Archer A6 or A7 Router Configuration Instructions For volunteer installers and DIY installers</description></item><item><title>TP-Link Indoor Router</title><link>/installs/tp-link/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/installs/tp-link/</guid><description>An indoor router, connected by ethernet cable to the outdoor router, is required for an NYC Mesh member to connect their personal devices to the Internet. For volunteer-led installations, the install team will supply the new member with a TP-Link dual-band router.
Here the link to configure the router</description></item><item><title>Try the new LTU sector</title><link>/hardware/ltu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/ltu/</guid><description>Ubiquiti has a new &amp;ldquo;technology&amp;rdquo; which is the successor to AirMax , called LTU. (more about AirMax )
LTU and AirMax are not compatible. You need a different device/antenna to connect to the LTU sector.
We have one LTU sector mounted on the west side of 1340-Saratoga. Try it. Here the approximate coverage.
The sector is a LTU-Rocket radio and a AM-5ac21-60 antenna. It is positioned about 260o azimut, and it&amp;rsquo;s a 60o angle.</description></item><item><title>Typical Installations</title><link>/intro/typical-installs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/intro/typical-installs/</guid><description>Please read our FAQ if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already.
The intention of this page is not to be technical but rather give to the non-technical person an understanding of a typical installation.
NYC Mesh is an &amp;ldquo;over the air&amp;rdquo; network. The aim is to connect rooftop to rooftop using different types of equipment based on geography and topology. And in doing so, to expand NYC Mesh network coverage to the next block and so on*.</description></item><item><title>Ubiquiti EdgePoint R6</title><link>/hardware/epr6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/epr6/</guid><description>The EP-R6 is an outdoor rooftop switch/router with 6 ports (5 GigE, 1 SFP). It supports PoE, but only Ubiquiti&amp;rsquo;s 24v Passive PoE style, not any of the fancier types.
It can be configured in switch mode (just a switch, with a management console) or routing mode (hub node setup, BGP, etc).
Device specs are available at store.ubnt.com.
Reset To factory reset an EP-R6, press and hold the reset button, by the ethernet plugs, for about 10 seconds until the eth4 LED begins to flash, then release the button.</description></item><item><title>Ubiquiti LiteAP Sector</title><link>/hardware/liteap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/liteap/</guid><description>The confusingly named LiteAP (LAP-120) is a very good, cheap 120&amp;rsquo; sector antenna. 120&amp;rsquo; means you need three to get a full 360&amp;rsquo;. It used to be called a LiteBeam 5AC AP LBE-5AC-16-120, and is still named that on parts of their website.
We use it as a sector antenna for most hub and supernode installs. As with all Ubiquiti gear you need to flash it with the latest firmware first.</description></item><item><title>Ubiquiti LiteBeam AC</title><link>/hardware/litebeamac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/litebeamac/</guid><description>The LiteBeamAC is a very good, cheap directional router. We use it for most rooftop installs. As with all Ubiquiti gear you need to flash it with the latest firmware first. Often they ship with old beta firmware, and the latest firmware usually gets you faster speeds. Our config instructions are here.
The AC in the name is not 802.11ac, it is Ubiquiti&amp;rsquo;s own protocol. These devices can only connect to other Ubiquiti &amp;ldquo;AC&amp;rdquo; devices.</description></item><item><title>Ubiquiti Nanostation M5</title><link>/hardware/nsm5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/nsm5/</guid><description>The NanoStation M5 is a workhorse of mesh networks. There are two versions XM (pre 2016) and XW. It is 802.11n and 10/100 ethernet, so not the fastest on the block, but it has good support from OpenWRT. It also has two ethernet ports usually set up as WAN and LAN. Recent versions require downgrading AirOS before you flash.
For new installs we use the OmniTik router for meshing. The following page is mainly for our legacy installs.</description></item><item><title>Unifi Access Points</title><link>/hardware/unifi-ap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hardware/unifi-ap/</guid><description>We are using more UNIFI access points on installs these days. These devices are very frustrating to set up, so this document is designed to help.
As of 2021 the latest firmware 4.3.28 has very short uptime (&amp;lt;30 days), so we are using a stable older version 4.3.20 (copy this link)
Never use 4.3.28 or later, as the device will go down and require a site visit to reboot!
The devices are coming with very old firmware that isn&amp;rsquo;t even compatible with the controller so step one is to SSH into the AP and upgrade it to 4.</description></item><item><title>VPN</title><link>/networking/vpn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/vpn/</guid><description>The NYC Mesh Virtual Private Network (VPN) is a system that enables a computer that is physically disconnected from the rest of the NYC Mesh network (e.g., because it is too distant from existing nodes) to access the network. Put another way, it extends the NYC Mesh network to computers that are not physically part of the mesh. This is used for a number of different purposes, including to provide access to intra-mesh services, ease new node installations, bootstrap new neighborhoods, and more.</description></item><item><title>VPN - L2TP/IPsec</title><link>/networking/vpnl2tpipsec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/vpnl2tpipsec/</guid><description>L2TP/IPSec is a common general-purpose VPN protocol that work with most platforms. For example, computers running Windows, macOS, iPhones, and Android devices all support this type of VPN out-of-the-box. This type of VPN is a little bit oldschool, in that it is typically found in enterprise corporate environments, which is part of what makes it so ubiquitous. For this reason, we have decided to provide and endpoint of this protocol.</description></item><item><title>VPN - L2TP/IPsec Req.</title><link>/networking/vpnl2tpipsecid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/vpnl2tpipsecid/</guid><description>NYC Mesh maintains some common VPN infrastructure for use by active mesh members.
Please feel free to use the VPNs. However, please note that NYC Mesh is not a commercial VPN provider or reseller, nor are we trying to achieve an Internet-based darknet. The VPN service is subject to change and/or breakage at any time. Do not rely on NYC Mesh’s VPN service as your primary or critical VPN provider. Also, as with all NYC Mesh resources, do not abuse the VPN service or the access it provides.</description></item><item><title>VPN - WireGuard</title><link>/networking/vpnwireguard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/vpnwireguard/</guid><description>WireGuard is a new, simple, and fast VPN implementation and protocol. For comparison, the older L2TP/IPsec VPNs typically will achieve about 100Mbps, but WireGuard VPNs may reach speeds upward of 300-400Mbps on the same hardware, or higher on a high-end workstation.
In addition to its speed, WireGuard has some great features such as built-in roaming (a single encrypted packet moves the tunnel to your new IP), cryptokey routing, and formal cryptographic verification.</description></item><item><title>VPN - WireGuard + OSPF</title><link>/networking/vpnwireguardospf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/networking/vpnwireguardospf/</guid><description>WireGuard is generally described on another page, here: [VPN - Wireguard]({{ relref &amp;ldquo;vpnwireguard.md&amp;rdquo;}}). This page is about what is needed to configure WireGuard for routing over the VPN; especially with a focus on OSPF.
A Note on Cryptokey Routing It&amp;rsquo;s worth a section to touch on the cryptokey routing feature of WireGuard and how it works with the mesh.
All WireGuard nodes list their peers in a configuration file. Among the peer configuration is a public key and a list of acceptable IP ranges for the peer.</description></item><item><title>Watchdog</title><link>/software/watchdog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/software/watchdog/</guid><description>Wireless networks have a bit of a reputation for instability. Modern hardware has fixed most hardware problems, but there is work that needs to be done to make the firmware reliable. You can do this with &amp;ldquo;watchdog&amp;rdquo; scripts. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had to reboot a router that is running our watchdog script.
Our firmware image (based on qMp) comes with a &amp;ldquo;bmx6health&amp;rdquo; script that checks whether the mesh software is running correctly and restarts it if necessary.</description></item><item><title>Workflow</title><link>/organization/workflow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/organization/workflow/</guid><description>Overview Join Form
Everything begins when a user fills out our Join Form.
Submitting it assigns the user a node number, sends a support ticket, and adds a row to a spredsheet in Google Docs we refer to as our &amp;ldquo;main spreadsheet.&amp;rdquo;
Main Spreadsheet
New nodes are displayed as gray dots on our map. They are rendered from the spreadsheet using the map-nodes code on our Github.
Support Ticketing
We use OSTicket for support tickets</description></item></channel></rss>